[{"id": "5febd6f97e83c707845b2170", "question": "When was the first year the three-point shot was introduced to the NBA?", "answer": "1979", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396fd", "question": "Who starred as Rocky Balboa?", "answer": "Sylvester Stallone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cf4e877e98cb97778a4d", "question": "What is the largest borough of New York City?", "answer": "Queens", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a689", "question": "Which US state is home to the manmade Fort Peck Lake?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af256d4b63e5727cf5a4840", "question": "What movie franchise action figures did Kenner start producing in the 1970s that led to its success and the popularization of the 3.75 inch action figure?", "answer": "Star Wars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e7c106d333868d34d742", "question": "In what movie theater was Lee Harvey Oswald arrested following the assassination of JFK?", "answer": "The Texas Theater", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9fe", "question": "Hawaii's Kalaupapa was known as a refuge for those suffering from what disease?", "answer": "Leprosy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81fb7d0de9af39e9d4698", "question": "What state had the first paved road in the U.S.?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3281ff048f679a45aae7", "question": "How many patents did Thomas Edison accumulate during his lifetime?", "answer": "2332 worldwide (1,093 in the US)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d89", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Shawn Carter?", "answer": "Jay-Z", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7b2cff048f679a45abf3", "question": "What arctic sea whale has one long horn on its head?", "answer": "Narwhal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddaff6ce05a3942286d8c", "question": "What store in Diagon Alley sells ingredients for potion making?", "answer": "The Apothecary", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b094", "question": "What country's transcontinental railway was finally finished on November 7, 1885?", "answer": "Canada's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bbd50ca00d154d7af00b8d8", "question": "Scott Raynor is the original drummer of which rock band?", "answer": "Blink-182", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae40", "question": "What was John F. Kennedy's wife's maiden name?", "answer": "Bouvier", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924e", "question": "Who plays Will Turner in the movie \"Pirates of the Caribbean\"?", "answer": "Orlando Bloom", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c7fa877e98cb977789da", "question": "In which capital city would you find the Marley Museum?", "answer": "Kingston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5e", "question": "What literary work inspired the Beatles' \"Tomorrow Never Knows\" song?", "answer": "The Tibetan Book of the Dead", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590722c63745b36be7303a02", "question": "What year did Mariah Carey release the song \"All I Want for Christmas Is You\"?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b645", "question": "What company produced the Cabbage Patch Kids dolls until 1989?", "answer": "Coleco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b8e2e662d71a53651029", "question": "The line \"All of this happened, more or less.\" starts what novel?", "answer": "\"Slaughterhouse-Five\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f34", "question": "Which band member of The Germs died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Darby Crash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a68f", "question": "Charleston is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "West Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5eb734555e259d7869087328", "question": "Which US president went on record saying that he wished he could\u2019ve hanged his vice president during his administration?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a11", "question": "On the TV show \"The West Wing\", Jed Bartlett was governor of which state before being elected president?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be00", "question": "What feline was the first-ever character balloon in the Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade?", "answer": "Felix the Cat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd4", "question": "In 1991, who erected three thousand blue and yellow umbrellas on the coasts of California and Japan?", "answer": "Christo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfe01c3b668d7dfe168b5c9", "question": "Who topped the UK album charts in 1990 with \"...But Seriously\"?", "answer": "Phil Collins", "category": "entertanment"}, {"id": "5a899d1360d398dc9cf7a6a9", "question": "John F. Kennedy Airport was originally named what?", "answer": "Idlewild Airport", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d8", "question": "What is the more common name for the fruit \"Citrus maxima\"?", "answer": "Pomelo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8a", "question": "What cartoon duo gave us the \"Happy Happy Joy Joy\" song?", "answer": "Ren & Stimpy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339707", "question": "What pirate's treasure is at the center of the kids' search in \"The Goonies\"?", "answer": "One-Eyed Willie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b1", "question": "Who became the chairman of the Truth and Reconciliation Commission in 1995?", "answer": "Archbishop Desmond Tutu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff6", "question": "What is Johnny Chase's nickname on the TV show \"Entourage\"?", "answer": "Drama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede5766ce05a3942286ded", "question": "What was the first cooking show on television, hosted by James Beard in 1946, called?", "answer": "\"I Love to Eat\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be44", "question": "What is the only fruit to be ever banned from airplanes?", "answer": "Durian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b81", "question": "Who played Jill Taylor on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Patricia Richardson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339278", "question": "What country singer was the first person to \"turn a chair\" on season 2 of the TV show \"The Voice\"?", "answer": "Rae Lynn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c97d", "question": "What constellation is Polaris located in?", "answer": "Ursa Minor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb4", "question": "In telephony, what do the initials ISDN stand for?", "answer": "Integrated Services for Digital Network", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec89cfec223966ae8f882a", "question": "In which 2000 movie did George Clooney play Captain Billy Tyne?", "answer": "\"A Perfect Storm\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a6", "question": "What nation was led by Alexander the Great?", "answer": "Macedon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d08071a1c922dd1ac64be", "question": "What is the capital of Mongolia?", "answer": "Ulaanbaatar, or formerly Ulan Bator", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a290", "question": "What name did Cat Stevens adopt in 1977?", "answer": "Yusuf Islam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133941c", "question": "What was the name of Marky Mark's backing band?", "answer": "The Funky Bunch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4cf", "question": "What name is given to trees that lose their leaves annually?", "answer": "Deciduous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c215", "question": "Which country hosted the first Winter Olympic Games after World War II?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173f9544491cbd7c5a17b3", "question": "What was the name Chuck Yeager gave to the Bell X-1 plane he used to break the sound barrier?", "answer": "\"Glamorous Glennis\" -- The plane was nicknamed after his wife.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c712", "question": "What hormone secreted by the pancreas lowers blood glucose levels in diabetics?", "answer": "Insulin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b2", "question": "What athlete played co-pilot Roger Murdock in the 1980 movie \"Airplane!\"?", "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f4e3fa5fdd6dd25324e8", "question": "What country borders Central African Republic to the west?", "answer": "Cameroon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d72", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Modern Prometheus\"?", "answer": "Frankenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bb356992627b8fe95581bdf", "question": "What is the name of the tallest flagpole in the world?", "answer": "The Jeddah Flagpole", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5921fcfba4edfd43a087adc7", "question": "What number is represented by \"M\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "1,000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90b", "question": "What major river runs through Cleveland?", "answer": "Cuyahoga", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc7", "question": "Taal is an alternative name for what language?", "answer": "Afrikaans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f16506df9b80650dbe7f93b", "question": "Where is ESPN's headquarters located?", "answer": "Bristol, Connecticut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea83f4ff048f679a45ac2e", "question": "What is the most common type of rock found on Earth's surface?", "answer": "Sedimentary", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa0", "question": "What is the capital of Niger?", "answer": "Niamey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ea", "question": "What TV show began with the words \"There is nothing wrong with your television set.\"?", "answer": "The Outer Limits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339996", "question": "For what 2005 film did George Clooney win a Best Supporting Actor Oscar?", "answer": "Syriana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb72", "question": "What was pictured on the face of the US penny just prior to Abraham Lincoln?", "answer": "Indian head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60136f3c1381754895396374", "question": "What is the only substance Superman cannot see through?", "answer": "Lead -- Real X-rays cannot penetrate lead, and writers latched onto that fact to keep Supes from being all-powerful.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c941", "question": "What is a group of larks called?", "answer": "Exaltation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be85", "question": "For what mysterious figure is the latch on the inside of some Boeing passenger jet doors named?", "answer": "D. B. Cooper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e0c", "question": "What quested-for treasure of Greek myth was the skin of the winged ram Chrysomallos?", "answer": "The Golden Fleece", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb8", "question": "Which tennis star's father represented Iran at boxing in two Olympic Games?", "answer": "Andre Agassi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a218", "question": "Who won the first UK version of \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Craig Phillips", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339138", "question": "Whose alias is \"The Man of Bronze\" in popular literature?", "answer": "Doc Savage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f1", "question": "In Poker, five cards of the same suit is called a what?", "answer": "Flush", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59decf04ea2747c8aff16d19", "question": "Which group recorded the albums \"Regatta de Blanc\" and \"Ghost in the Machine\"?", "answer": "The Police", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3ea4438e4e5d4832e6314", "question": "Which U.S. President started the tradition of having a national Christmas tree on the White House lawn?", "answer": "Calvin Coolidge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbc", "question": "Which country was split into zones by the 'Yalta Agreement'?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a33", "question": "Who played the Reverend Jim Ignatowski on the TV show \"Taxi\"?", "answer": "Christopher Lloyd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec9", "question": "Kim Kardashian and Kanye West\u2019s second baby\u2019s name is what?", "answer": "Saint", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c56", "question": "What was the name of Whitney Houston's 1985 debut album?", "answer": "Whitney Houston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b1745a8bb2d29f81593b702", "question": "If music was played leggiero, how should it be done?", "answer": "Lightly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e64", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Inspector Gadget?", "answer": "Don Adams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b572", "question": "What is Grappa?", "answer": "An Alcoholic Drink", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339997", "question": "What TV sidekick was portrayed by Jay Silverheels?", "answer": "Tonto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ed7", "question": "The journey in Roald Dahl's \"James and the Giant Peach\" ends with the peach impaled on what?", "answer": "The Empire State Building", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338abe", "question": "Which author and philosopher is known for his works The Plague, The Outsider and The Fall?", "answer": "Albert Camus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb97", "question": "What type of building or facility gets its name from the Greek meaning \"to exercise naked\"?", "answer": "Gymnasium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d3a32596a59cbdfbd39c", "question": "What skyrocketed Apple to fame in 1984?", "answer": "A Superbowl ad", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c70c", "question": "Something which is an \"emetic\" makes you do what?", "answer": "Vomit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b311", "question": "Peter the Great is considered the founding father of what country?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a666", "question": "What US city is home to the International UFO Museum and Research Center?", "answer": "Roswell", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5ee66ce05a3942286e3b", "question": "Kyle Korver is frequently mistaken for which famous actor?", "answer": "Ashton Kutcher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a2", "question": "How long do rodeo bull and bronco riders have to stay on their mounts for?", "answer": "8 seconds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b7", "question": "Who played the role of Ricky Stratton on the TV show \"Silver Spoons\"?", "answer": "Ricky Schroeder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea46ffff048f679a45aba7", "question": "What does \"PO\" stand for on a prescription?", "answer": "By mouth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339194", "question": "Who is \"The Fastest Mouse in all Mexico\"?", "answer": "Speedy Gonzales", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a2e", "question": "What university did David Letterman graduate from in 1969 with a degree in telecommunications?", "answer": "Ball State", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded09aea2747c8aff16d2a", "question": "What is extracted from the ore cassiterite?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b45", "question": "What does the Giant smell when he says \"Fee, Fi, Foe, Fum\"?", "answer": "The blood of an Englishman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b178", "question": "When did the Sydney Opera House officially open its doors to the public?", "answer": "20 October 1973", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f8", "question": "In the movie \"Pulp Fiction\", what is the name of the restaurant Mia brings Vincent to?", "answer": "Jack-Rabbit Slim's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda9", "question": "What two people appear in the famous photo taken aboard the yacht Monkey Business in May 1987?", "answer": "Gary Hart and Donna Rice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee6", "question": "What hit sitcom was based on the 1964 Tony Randall film \"The Brass Bottle\"?", "answer": "I Dream of Jeannie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5de", "question": "Who was the model for the official NBA logo?", "answer": "Jerry West", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b26d", "question": "What ship carried Captain Cook to Australia?", "answer": "Endeavour", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133901a", "question": "Who painted the \"Rockeby Venus\"?", "answer": "Diego Velazquez", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a9", "question": "Where did Chris Farley\u2019s SNL character Matt Foley live?", "answer": "In a van", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c1e", "question": "Which rabbit was the hero of some of Beatrix Potters stories?", "answer": "Peter Rabbit", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab0", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Austria?", "answer": "Barn Swallow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af8c", "question": "What was the primary source of food for the Comanche Indians?", "answer": "American bison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e7", "question": "What is a spinnaker on a boat?", "answer": "Type of sail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae85e994007905755f79e88", "question": "Though not published first, which book in \"The Chronicles of Narnia\" series comes first chronologically?", "answer": "The Magician\u2019s Nephew", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b94e", "question": "What common legal item literally means \"under penalty\"?", "answer": "Subpoena", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e3f3965cb9e8bda6821364", "question": "When was the Rosetta Stone found?", "answer": "1799", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9cc", "question": "What is another term for the sternum?", "answer": "Breastbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feccdbaec223966ae8f88ad", "question": "In \"Gone With the Wind\", what gift does Rhett bring back from New Orleans for Mammy?", "answer": "A petticoat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b20c", "question": "In which nation did the woven-yarn craft of \"God's eyes\" originate?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d0", "question": "What baseball team suffered from the \"Curse of the Bambino\"?", "answer": "Boston Red Sox", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ea9308d98002fdd633a4", "question": "With what body part is otology involved?", "answer": "The Ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae7", "question": "In what year did both \"Mad Magazine\" and \"The National Enquirer\" debut?", "answer": "1952", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba3e5874c93a3298b2141", "question": "What actress played Laura and Almanzo's niece on the \"Little House on the Prairie\"?", "answer": "Shannen Doherty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65785ae7e414034b5aedc", "question": "Where did Britain restore parliamentary powers after Sinn Fein agreed to disarm?", "answer": "Northern Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd64", "question": "In what US state are submarine sandwiches traditionally called \"po' boys\"?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec26118dc25ca9e12ef645", "question": "London's Trafalgar Square Christmas tree is traditionally given by which country?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c4", "question": "When did Indira Gandhi's first term as Prime Minister of India begin?", "answer": "1966", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af59", "question": "What was the name for the military trials held in 1945 and 1946 to prosecute Nazi leaders?", "answer": "Nuremberg Trials", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ea", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \" Good evening, everyone, and welcome to a wonderful evening of theater and picking up after yourselves", "answer": "Principal Skinner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b14e", "question": "With what nation did the US sign the Paris Peace Accords in 1973?", "answer": "North Vietnam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfff", "question": "Who is known as \"Big Mama\" in ladies pro golf?", "answer": "JoAnne Carner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e7", "question": "What is the longest one syllable word in the English language?", "answer": "Screeched", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a193", "question": "Which famous voice-over artist played Woody Woodpecker in his first few cartoons?", "answer": "Mel Blanc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc3906ce05a3942286f24", "question": "Lindsey Buckingham is the lead guitarist for what British-American band?", "answer": "Fleetwood Mac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2b", "question": "What Internet portal was sued for copyright infringement in 2000 by the star of \"Young Einstein\"?", "answer": "Yahoo!", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c481", "question": "What is a group of feral horses called?", "answer": "A band", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a67120565ad31a57c7d9", "question": "What is the name of the first nuclear-powered merchant ship?", "answer": "NS Savannah", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fbf", "question": "Who wrote the short novel \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339984", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what was the name of Barney's snowplowing business?", "answer": "Plow King", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be09", "question": "What NFL team replaced its AFL-era horse logo with a bolt of lightning?", "answer": "The San Diego Chargers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c405", "question": "The loose skin hanging from the neck of a chicken is known as a what?", "answer": "Wattle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fde5107c6c6b019850c9a8c", "question": "Mariner IV sent the first pictures of which planet back to Earth?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339359", "question": "What does the \"D.J.\" stand for in D.J. Tanner's name in the TV show \"Full House\"?", "answer": "Donna Jo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339205", "question": "In what movie does Eddie Murphy swap identities with Dan Aykroyd?", "answer": "Trading Places", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab25", "question": "What is the capital of Madagascar?", "answer": "Antananarivo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc2f63fcee580c7f8fd1e5c", "question": "What was the leading cause of combatants' deaths during the American Civil War?", "answer": "Disease", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6b", "question": "In the game \"Joust\", what animal was your mount?", "answer": "An Ostritch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339641", "question": "What is the name of Thor's hammer?", "answer": "Mjolnir", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600a274ee958e8c9f3127314", "question": "Who is the city of Regina, Saskatchewan named for?", "answer": "Queen Victoria - Originally a hunters\u2019 camp named Pile O\u2019Bones, the settlement was renamed Regina, Latin for \"queen\".", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339212", "question": "What rock star is credited as a co-writer and backing singer for David Bowie's \"Fame\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedd9e06ce05a3942286d7d", "question": "What was the first movie to be rated PG-13?", "answer": "\"Red Dawn\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989acb0cb8751d53e7d760c", "question": "Which two twin primes add up to 360?", "answer": "179 and 181", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339919", "question": "What was John Ritter\u2019s character\u2019s name in the TV show \"Three\u2019s Company\"?", "answer": "Jack Tripper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000ece89a72b906b34e3ce7", "question": "The only known monotremes in the animal kingdom are the echidna and which other creature?", "answer": "Platypus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339883", "question": "In Harry Potter, who is it that reveals to Harry that he is a wizard?", "answer": "Hagrid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb69685dad637d903c8847", "question": "Who played the wife of Goose in the film \"Top Gun\"?", "answer": "Meg Ryan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6661ca5bfecdd737e0865", "question": "Where is Apple Inc. headquartered?", "answer": "Cupertino, California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7359deec85e375820b24e", "question": "Who said, \"Courage is what it takes to stand up and speak, it\u2019s also what it takes to sit down and listen.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8a", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is O'Shea Jackson?", "answer": "Ice Cube", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e3", "question": "What city is the capital of New York State?", "answer": "Albany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c220", "question": "When did \"Macho Man\" Randy Savage die?", "answer": "2011", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d9", "question": "What is Merlin's owl name in Disney's film \"The Sword in the Stone\"?", "answer": "Archimedes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef96566ce05a3942286e9c", "question": "The novel \"Flowers for Algernon\" became which major motion picture?", "answer": "\"Charly\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9baa1364247bf200fb89a", "question": "What is the fear of death known as?", "answer": "Necrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c238", "question": "What did Harry Houdini die from on Halloween in 1926?", "answer": "Ruptured appendix", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec5", "question": "In what year was the hit game \"Minecraft\" released?", "answer": "2009", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2eb", "question": "What US state has been led by Hannibal Hamlin and Edmund Muskie?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb5", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Lasky?", "answer": "Grape", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa4019c73aa70ea0b70b07", "question": "Which district in central Tokyo is particularly famous for its electronics?", "answer": "Akihabara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c670", "question": "Who won a Grammy Award for his song \"I Left my Heart in San Francisco\"?", "answer": "Tony Bennett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d9922596a59cbdfbd3c7", "question": "Which Joseph Glidden invention put an end to open-range cattle drives?", "answer": "Barbed wire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7eaebb24f84e0b9f9ffd9", "question": "What was Richard Wagner's second Opera that was inspired by a trip on the sea?", "answer": "The Flying Dutchman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2f", "question": "Choreographer and actor Chris Judd was what actress and singer's second husband?", "answer": "Jennifer Lopez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e9", "question": "What was the first animated feature nominated for a best picture Oscar?", "answer": "Beauty and the Beast", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f3f7caf848b908361b86c", "question": "What do the numbers on a roulette wheel add up to?", "answer": "666", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e8", "question": "What is absent in \"negative\" blood types like O negative and AB negative?", "answer": "Rhesus antigens", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a59b", "question": "What Canadian province is home to Pink Mountain, Muncho Lake and Nootka Sound?", "answer": "British Columbia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c13b877e98cb97778976", "question": "Which two US states are connected by the Natchez\u2013Vidalia Bridge?", "answer": "Mississippi and Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad6", "question": "Who wrote King George V Christmas speech that was broadcast in 1932?", "answer": "Rudyard Kipling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5aab2e6958d116dab4aecb3e", "question": "Inanna is the ancient Sumerian goddess of what?", "answer": "Love, fertility and war", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c428", "question": "Where in the body will you find your aqueous humour?", "answer": "Eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc0", "question": "Tirana is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Albania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c50", "question": "Who directed the 1968 \"Planet of the Apes\" movie?", "answer": "Franklin J. Schaffner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d7", "question": "Who won an Oscar for his role in the film 'The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904a3b3cf93664eb10486bf", "question": "Who created the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\"?", "answer": "Terry Moore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e1", "question": "Mycology is the study of what?", "answer": "Fungi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a984", "question": "In what Caribbean country did steel drums originate?", "answer": "Trinidad and Tobago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a334", "question": "Which UK band had a hit in the 1980's with the song \"Sonic Boom Boy\"?", "answer": "Westworld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19f", "question": "Construction of the Tower of Pisa was completed in what year?", "answer": "1372", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d34", "question": "Who's responsible for performing \"The Ballad of John and Yoko\"?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a974661d1b4d384d5d682", "question": "What nationality is designer Karl Lagerfield?", "answer": "German", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b65ae662d71a53651006", "question": "Who played Anita in the first Broadway production of West Side Story?", "answer": "Chita Rivera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e9", "question": "Which actor received the first Academy Award?", "answer": "Emil Jannings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d6752596a59cbdfbd3ab", "question": "What organization unveiled the largest machine on Earth in 2008?", "answer": "CERN", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c8770775fa611bce67e0", "question": "\"En masse\" translates to what?", "answer": "In a group", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58bb351de368446ca7bd684e", "question": "What chemical reaction during roasting is chiefly responsible for giving green coffee beans their flavor?", "answer": "Maillard Reaction", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5904a40fcf93664eb10486c1", "question": "Despite being referred to as Francine throughout the \"Strangers in Paradise\" comic book series, what is this character\u2019s real first name?", "answer": "Helen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133956f", "question": "Who wrote the made-for-TV special, A Charlie Brown Christmas?", "answer": "Charles M. Shulz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c957", "question": "Approximately how many miles is an Astronomical Unit?", "answer": "93 million", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c617", "question": "How many chromosomes are in human DNA?", "answer": "46", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c152", "question": "What is a group of locusts called?", "answer": "Plague", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a4", "question": "Who released the albums \"At Folsom Prison\" and \"At San Quentin\"?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59564403803c1f1ebcc4a033", "question": "Ketchup was sold in the 1830\u2019s as what?", "answer": "Medicine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c21", "question": "In Douglas Adams' Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy, what do the Vogons use to torture prisoners?", "answer": "Poetry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bb35b4f2627b8fe95581beb", "question": "In ABC's \"Once Upon a Time\" what character was played by Colin O' Donoghue?", "answer": "Captain Hook", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e0", "question": "What term is given to the scientific study of all aspects of the life of fungi?", "answer": "Mycology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594125b6bab1e6f9796f1b56", "question": "What two colors are on the flag of Israel?", "answer": "Blue and white", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2145331a458464a93c455", "question": "Which Thanksgiving favorite did Marcus L. Urann invent?", "answer": "Cranberry sauce", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5b", "question": "Which British actor played Basil Fawlty in the TV show \"Fawlty Towers\"?", "answer": "John Cleese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b82e", "question": "What does the abbreviation NASCAR stand for?", "answer": "National Association for Stock Car Auto Racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008ff3cf842fa4c4ba96c2", "question": "Who created the fictional character Tristram Shandy?", "answer": "Laurence Sterne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338912", "question": "What flowers did van Gogh paint most regularly?", "answer": "Sunflowers", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f0", "question": "HBO's TV show \"True Blood\" is based on a book series by whom?", "answer": "Charlene Harris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65dbc1f3c0ead6880d620", "question": "What did God place at the east of the Garden of Eden after he drove out Adam and Eve?", "answer": "Cherubims", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7b5", "question": "What animal does California have on its state flag?", "answer": "Bear", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feba8ef7e83c707845b20cf", "question": "How many eyelids does a duck have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f16ae3f7c52aae91cc07e2", "question": "What sort of food are \"rollmops\"?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b17", "question": "What was the first name of Julia Roberts' character in the 2001 movie \"Ocean's Eleven\"?", "answer": "Tess", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a3", "question": "\"Coulrophobia\" is the fear of what?", "answer": "Clowns", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cef", "question": "What artist performed the song titled \"Doo Wop\"?", "answer": "Lauryn Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe37ba40ada16518afdc060", "question": "Approximately how many US marines fought at the Battle of Guadalcanal?", "answer": "19,000", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71e", "question": "With what do you \"Deck the Halls\"?", "answer": "Boughs of Holly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c85e", "question": "What does a hygrometer measure?", "answer": "Humidity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b571b1967df192a942e3364", "question": "What is the name of the dog on the Cracker Jack box?", "answer": "Bingo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90b", "question": "In 2009 what did the \"Sears Tower\" had its name changed to?", "answer": "Willis Tower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6f", "question": "What was the name of Rhett and Scarlett\u2019s daughter in \"Gone With the Wind\"?", "answer": "Bonnie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8fb5101dd7bf43be5e850", "question": "A Sidecar cocktail contains triple sec, lemon juice and what?", "answer": "Cognac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59412872bab1e6f9796f1b5d", "question": "Who composed \"Symphonie fantastique\"?", "answer": "Hector Berlioz", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da7", "question": "What breed of dog is Snoopy?", "answer": "Beagle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c8a6fb90aac110e4167082", "question": "How many milliliters is a teaspoon?", "answer": "5 mL", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf3", "question": "What supermodel was engaged to U2\u2019s bass guitarist Adam Clayton during the 1990\u2019s?", "answer": "Naomi Campbell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9d2", "question": "What word is used for a male deer?", "answer": "Buck", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988d", "question": "Which South African femal singer was known as Mama Africa?", "answer": "Miriam Makeba", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a34a12f2a7826b9b8724", "question": "What was E.T.'s favorite candy?", "answer": "Recee's Pieces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4a", "question": "What is the name for Germany's high-speed highways?", "answer": "Autobahn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baaa", "question": "\"Double Your Pleasure, Double Your Fun\" was an ad slogan used by what product?", "answer": "Wrigley's Doublemint Gum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25aa1b63e5727cf5a4855", "question": "Which song was featured in the 1991 film \"Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves\" and held the number one spot in the UK singles chart for 16 weeks?", "answer": "(Everything I Do) I Do It for You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6f", "question": "Edam cheese comes from what country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff5136bff04d658268c92da", "question": "Who was the first First Lady of the United States to wear pants in public?", "answer": "Eleanor Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a131", "question": "Who created the TV show \"Jeeves and Wooster\"?", "answer": "Clive Exton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339384", "question": "In the movie \"Stand By Me\", what cartoon character does Vern think can take Superman on?", "answer": "Mighty Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c263", "question": "What grows in a paddy field?", "answer": "Rice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59412664bab1e6f9796f1b58", "question": "How long does a day last on Uranus?", "answer": "17 hours", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a034", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", which US president has been seen happily singing in public about being nude?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339469", "question": "Who drinks Tim's lava lamp in the 1999 movie \"My Favourite Martian\"?", "answer": "Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a574", "question": "What is the largest bay in Rhode Island?", "answer": "Narragansett Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a065", "question": "According to the song what did my true love give to me on the fifth day of Christmas?", "answer": "Five gold rings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8a9da01dd7bf43be5e753", "question": "Why did Jack and Jill go up the hill?", "answer": "Fetch a pail of water", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a821", "question": "Botany Bay lies off the coast of what country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b323331bf195a31e15d7398", "question": "What is the capital of Botswana?", "answer": "Gaborone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded386ea2747c8aff16d49", "question": "What does a hygrometer measure?", "answer": "Water vapour in atmosphere i.e. Humidity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fcc1d53c97eb73f6a51a277", "question": "Which is farther north, Newfoundland or Great Britain?", "answer": "Great Britain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339334", "question": "What was Lucille Ball's TV nickname?", "answer": "The First Lady of Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f79", "question": "What was Marky Mark's backing band?", "answer": "The Funky Bunch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd6127e83c707845b2169", "question": "What member of an acting family dated Taylor Swift, and is rumored to be the ex in her song, \"We Are Never Getting Back Together\"?", "answer": "Jake Gyllenhaal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d1f22596a59cbdfbd389", "question": "In the film \"The Hustler,\" who played the role of Minnesota Fats?", "answer": "Jackie Gleason", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e98d7ebfabb9c85d8a96f", "question": "What is the capital of Honduras?", "answer": "Tegucigalpa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933b", "question": "On the TV show \"South Park\", which character wears a blue hat with a red pom-pom on it?", "answer": "Stan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d41", "question": "What was Dutch painter Rembrandt's full name?", "answer": "Rembrandt Harmenszoon van Rijn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5989ae68cb8751d53e7d7615", "question": "The dance called the \"Maxixe\" is also known by what name?", "answer": "Brazilian Tango", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb1a865ff7d326b622a6c", "question": "As what is Beethoven's piano sonata in C-sharp minor more commonly known?", "answer": "The Moonlight Sonata", "category": "arts"}]